Inventory of the Larry Eigner Papers
Department of Special Collections
Larry Eigner papers
1937-1995
M0902
Eigner, Larry, 1927-
15.75 linear feet
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Personal papers through 1996, including all his poetry manuscripts arranged in sequence of composition by Eigner himself. Also literary and family correspondence, prose manuscripts, notebooks and juvenilia of Larry Eigner.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Richard M. and Beverly Eigner, 1996 and 1997. Accession numbers 1996-256, 1997-006, 1997-190.
Biography / Administrative History
American poet born in Swampscott, MA, Eigner was confined his entire life to a wheelchair as a result of cerebral palsy. Educated at home by his parents, he lived with them in Swampscott until 1978, when he moved to California. Eigner's writing reflects his special perspective on the world, developing a distinctive style to register his uniquely distanced vision of the world. His first volume of poetry From the Sustaining Air was published in 1953 by Robert Creeley. His steady productivity resulted in numerous subsequent collections, including, Another Time in Fragments (1967), Things Stirring/ Together/ or Far Away (1974), now there's-a-morning-hulk of the sky (1981), and Waters/Places/ A Time (1983). His short stories are collected in Farther North (1969) and his prose writings in Country/ Harbour/ Quiet/ Act/ Around: Selected Prose (1978) and Area/ Lights/ Heights: Selected Writings, 1954 -1989. His latest book of poetry is Windows/ Walls/ Yard/ Ways (1994), but at the time of his death he had just completed work on a new collection Readiness/ Enough/ Depends/ On, now forthcoming.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers include the typescripts of all of Eigner's poetry, arranged in sequence by the author, many with holographic notations by Eigner. Also included is correspondence to Eigner arranged alphabetically by the correspondent's name. Major correspondents include from Cid Corman, Clayton Eshleman, Arthur McFarland, James Weil, Douglas Woolf, and many others. There are also copies of some of Eigner's return correspondence.
Arrangement
Boxes #1 through #7 contain materials documenting Larry Eigner?s poetical works. These papers are arranged in the sequences Eigner himself devised and used. The papers consist predominantly of photocopy and carbon copies of typescripts, the originals of which are in the University of Kansas Library. Many of these copies do, however, have holographic notations, most of which are extremely difficult to read. There are some original manuscript works included, also with notations. Boxes #8 through #12 contain letters to Eigner arranged alphabetically by the correspondent?s name. Larger and more important files are from Cid Corman, Clayton Eshleman, Arthur McFarland, James Weil, and Douglas Woolf. Occasional copies of Eigner?s own letters are present and noted. The major exception to this pattern is the McFarland file which includes Eigner?s original correspondence to McFarland. Boxes 13-20 comprise the rest of the material from the original 1996 accession. Additional material from later accessions are found in Boxes 21-31.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Andrews, Bruce.; Charters, Sam.; Collom, Jack.; Corman, Cid.; Costley, Bill.; Fox, Hugh.; Fry, Fred R.; Gannick, Peter.; Grenier, Robert.; Hemensley, Kris.; Henny, Laurence.; Inman, Terence.; Koller, Jim.; MacLow, Jackson.; Martin, John.; Mazonson, Anne.; McClure, Michael.; Montgomery, Stuart.; Peabody, Richard.; Sorrentino, Gil.; Taggart, John.; Tyson, Montgomery.; Waylen, Christopher.; American literature--20th century.; Poets.
Container List
- Poetical Work Materials, Series 1
  - File #1: Poems labeled by Eigner #1 -110 / (1950 -1953, approx 120 pp also 8 misc. unnumbered poems. (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - File #2: Poems labeled by Eigner (2) - (k) (Fall 1953 - May 1955), approx 80 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - File #3: Poems labeled by Eigner (L) - (Z) (June 1955 - Sept 1957), approx 100 pp. (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
  - File #4: Poems labeled by Eigner (12) - (9k) (1957 - Oct 1959), approx 160pp. (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - File #5: Poems labeled by Eigner (2L) - (10Z) (Oct 1959 - Jan 7, 1961), approx 140pp. (Box 2, Folder 6-12)
  - File #6: Poems labeled by Eigner (ab) - (ce) (Feb 8, 1961 - Feb 2, 1962), approx 90pp. (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
    sorted by indices contained herein (D1-D8)
  - File #6: Poems labeled by Eigner (d4) - (eq) (Feb 14, 1962 - June 6, 1965), approx 90pp. (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - File #7: Poems labeled by Eigner (d5) - (ia) (March 29, 1964 - December 31, 1965), approx 140pp. (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    sorted by indices contained herein
  - File #8: Poems labeled by Eigner (ia) - (ks) (January 1, - June 21, 1966), approx 70pp. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - File #9: Poems labeled by Eigner #1-99 (June 29 - June 3, 1967) approx, 130pp. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - File #10: Poems labeled by Eigner #100 - 199 (June 19, 1967 - May 15, 1968), approx 140pp. (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - File #11: Poems labeled by Eigner #200 -299 (May 16, 1968 - March 28, 1969), approx 140pp. (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - File #12: Poems labeled by Eigner #300 - 399 (March 29, 1969 - June 16, 1970), approx 120pp. (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - File #13: Poems labeled by Eigner #400 - 499 (June 18, 1970 - May 3, 1971), approx 150pp. (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - File #14: Poems labeled by Eigner #500 - 599 (June 18, 1970 - May 3, 1971), approx 150pp. (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - File #15: Poems labeled by Eigner #600 - 699 (Dec 18, 1971 - June 26, 1972), Approx 120pp. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - File #16: Poems labeled by Eigner #700 - 799 (June 27, 1972 - July 30, 1973), Approx 100pp. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - File #17: Poems labeled by Eigner #800 - 899 (Aug 4, 1973 - Nov 25, 1974), Approx 160pp. (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - File #18: Poems labeled by Eigner #900 - 999 (Nov 26, 1974 - Jan 8, 1977), Approx 160pp. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - File #19: Poems labeled by Eigner #1000 - 1099 (Jan 15, 1977 - Oct 11, 1978), Approx 80pp. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - File #20: Poems labeled by Eigner #1100 - 1199 (Oct 11, 1978 - March 12, 1980), Approx 70pp. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - File #21: Poems labeled by Eigner #1200 - 1299 (March ?, 1980 - Dec 7, 1981), Approx 100pp. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - File #22: Poems labeled by Eigner #1300 - 1399 (Dec 12, 1981- June 7?, 1983), Approx 80pp. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - File #23: Poems labeled by Eigner #1400 - 1499 (July 6, 1983 - Feb 22, 1985), Approx 80pp. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - File #24: Poems labeled by Eigner #1500 - 1599 (Feb 22, 1985 - Jan 10, 1987), Approx 100pp. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - File #25: Poems labeled by Eigner #1600 - 1699 (Jan ?, 1987 - Nov 5, 1991), Approx 200pp. (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - File #26: Poems labeled by Eigner #1700 - 1799 (Nov 25, 1991 - Nov 17, 1995), Approx 250pp. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - File # 27: Photocopies of miscellaneous Eigner poems (unidentified with regard to chronology). (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- Correspondence, Series 2
  - #1: Letters from Larry Eigner to various correspondents (1966 -92), Approx 100pp. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - #2: Letters to Eigner from various British correspondents (1969-81), Approx 40pp. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - #3: Letters to Eigner from various French correspondents (1982-89), Approx 30pp. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - #4: Baracks, Barbara - Letters to Eigner (1973-75), 7pp. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - #5: Bernstein, Charles - Letters to Eigner (1982-89), 5pp. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - #6: Borash, Sam - Letters to Eigner (1979-84), 6pp. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - #7: Bowering, George - Letters to Eigner (1964 - 74), 10pp. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - #8: Boyle, Jim, - Letters to Eigner w/poetry (1964-66) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Approx 50pp (15 letters, 4 postcards).
  - #9: Brito, Manuel - Letters to Eigner (1991-94), 10pp. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - #10: Bromige, David - Letters to Eigner (1981), 6pp. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - #11: Bruce, Lennart & Sonja - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry (1967-79), Approx 50pp (32 letters, 3 postcards). (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - #12: Buck, Fred, - Letters to Eigner (1977) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    8pp.
  - #13: Buck, Paul - Letters to Eigner (1971-74), 11pp. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - #14: Butterick, George - Letters to Eigner (1974-75), 9pp. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - #15: Calhoun, Doug - Letters to Eigner (1973), 2pp. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - #16: Caplan, Ron - Letters to Eigner (1964-70), 7pp. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - #17: Carruth, Hayden - Letters to Eigner (1968-75), 3pp. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - #18: Charters, Ann & Sam - Letters to Eigner (1968 -74), Approx 20pp (16 letters, 1 postcard). (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - #19: Clark, Tom - Letters to Eigner (1965), 4pp. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - #20: Coolidge, Clark - Letters to Eigner (1974), 2pp. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - #21: Corman, Cid - Letters to Eigner (1986-95) Approx 40 pp, (13 letters, 4 postcards, 4 photocopies of replies from Eigner). (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - #22: Costley, Bill - Letters to Eigner (1967-86) Approx 25pp, (7 letters, 2 postcards). (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - #23: Creeley, Robert - Postcards & Letters to Eigner (1984-88), 4pp. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - #24: Davies, Alan - Letters to Eigner (1979-85), 6pp. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - #25: Eigner, Bessie - Letters to Eigner (1980-83), 3pp. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - #26: Eigner, Eddie - Letters to Eigner (1967-90), 4pp. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - #27: Eigner, Joe, Jan, & Alan - Letters to Eigner (1981-95), Approx 25pp (18 letters, 5 postcards). (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - #28: Eshleman, Clayton - Letters to Eigner w/copies of 2 Eigner letters to Eshleman (1981-92, Approx 20pp (15 letters, 1 postcard). (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - #29: Fagin, Larry - 3 poetry pamphlets (1979). (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - #30: Ferrini, Vincent- Letter to Eigner (1994, 1pp. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - #31: Foley, Jack & Adele - Letters to Eigner w/ copies of letters dictated by Eigner (1986-95), Approx 25pp (14 letters, 4 postcards, 1 reply from Eigner). (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - #32: Fowler, Gene - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry (1965-67), Approx 30pp (9 letters). (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - #33: Frazer, Larry - Letters to Eigner (1980-94), 12 letters. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - #34: Frefeld, Larry - Letters to Eigner (1970), 8pp. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - #35: Ganick, Peter - Letters to Eigner (1979-89), 4pp. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - #36: Gitin, David & Maria - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry (1969-94), Approx 80 pp (61 letters, 3 postcards). (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - #37: Goddell, Larry- Letter to Eigner w/ 2 poems (1972), 3pp. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - #38: Greene, Jonathan - Letter to Eigner w/ poem (1964), 2pp. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - #39: Grady, Robert - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry (1962-71), Approx 50 pp (23 letters, 4 cards). (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - #40: Grenier, Robert - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry(1970-71), Approx 20pp (10 letters, 3 cards, 1 reply from Eigner). (Box 9, Folder 18)
    some holographic notes by Eigner
  - #41: Harrison, Ollie - Letters to Eigner w/ clippings(1992-94), Approx 40pp (13 letters). (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - #42: Hawley, Robert (Oyez)- Letters to Eigner (1970-72), 5pp. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - #43: Irby, Kenneth - Letter to Eigner (1983), 1pp. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - #44: Hemensley, Bernard & Kris - Letters to Eigner (1979-84), Approx 40pp (24 letters, 3 postcards). (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - #45: Jay, Peter (Anvil Press) 2 Letters to Eigner w/ poem (1970), 3pp. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - #46: Landers, Dale - 2 Letters & 2 postcards to Eigner (1960) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    back of one letter used by Eigner to compose a poem on his typewriter dated Dec 16, 1960 (extremely fragile).
  - #47: Leif, Irving - Letters to Eigner (1979-81), Approx 30pp (21 letters, 1 postcard). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - #48: Levertov, Denise - Letter to Eigner (1987), 1pp. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - #49: Levy, John - Letters to Eigner (1983-85), 10pp. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - #50: MacLow, Jackson - Letters to Eigner (1970-82), 2pp. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - #51: McClure, Michael, 2pp. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Letter to Eigner (1994)
  - #52: McFarland, Arthur - Letters to Eigner (1967-83), Approx 200pp. (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    Including Eigner's letters to McFarland, as well as poetry written by Eigner on the back of received by him. (62 letters by McFarland - 38 letters and 14 postcard replies from Eigner).
  - #53: McNaughton, Duncan - Letters to Eigner (1993-95), 2pp. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - #54: Miller, Hugh - Letters to Eigner (1978-79), 17pp (8 letters). (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - #55: Malanga, Gerard - Letter to Eigner (undated), 1pp. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - #56: Marlatt, Daphne - Letters to Eigner (1969-77), 15pp. (9 letters, 1 postcard). (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - #57: Martin, John - Letters to Eigner (1968-88), 17pp (14 letters, 1 postcard). (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - #58: Martone, John - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry and essay (1987-95), Approx 30pp (16 letters, 2 postcards). (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - #59: Messerli, Douglas (Sun & Moon Press)- Letters to Eigner (1990-95), 3pp. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - #60: Montgomery, Stewart (Fulcrum Press) - Letter to Eigner (1970), 1pp. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - #61: Notley, Alice - Letter to Eigner (1991), 1pp. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - #62: Perlman, John - Letters to Eigner w/ poetry (1983-94), 10pp (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - #63: Perlman, Marilyn - Letters to Eigner w/clippings (1981-87), Approx 20pp (10 letters, 6 postcards). (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - #64: Raworth, Tom - Letter & postcard to Eigner (1986), 2pp. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - #65: Rowan, Louis - Letters to Eigner (1969), 6pp. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - #66: Sherry, James - Letters to Eigner (1978-90), 2pp. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - #67: Silliman, Ron - Letters to Eigner (1971-75), 7pp. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - #68: Sorrentino, Gilbert - Letters to Eigner (1983-94), 3pp. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - #69: Souster, Ray - Letter to Eigner (1963), 2pp. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - #70: Turnbull, Gael - Letters to Eigner (1985-87), 4pp. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - #71: Waldrop, Rosemarie & Keith - Letters to Eigner (1977-83), 5pp. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - #72: Watten, Barrett- 3 Letters to Eigner (undated), 4pp (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - #73: Weil, James - Letters to Eigner (1984-91), Approx 40pp (40 letters, 30 postcards) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - #74: Weissner, Carl - Letters to Eigner (1966-68), 12pp (7 letters and 2 postcards). (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - #75: Williams, Jonathan- Photocopy of a letter to Eigner (1978), 2pp (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - #76: Wilson, Keith - 3 letters to Eigner (1968-72), 4pp (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - #77: Woolf, Douglas - 12 1etters to Eigner (1978-90) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - #78: Wyatt, Andrea - 4 letters to Eigner w/ poem (1970 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Various Correspondence - (1962-95), Approx 400pp (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
    Includes letters from friends, admirers, and poets w/ poetry, photographs, solicitations for the inclusion of Eigner's work in publications, press notices, notes from publishers and editors of Eigner's work, postcards, flyers, birthday cards - some holographic notations by Eigner.
- Drafts, Manuscripts, and Notebooks, Series 3
  - #1: Draft: Typescripts (1970 - 1993), Approx 40pp. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Mostly on the backs of envelopes, some w/ holographic notations by Eigner,
  - #2: Manuscripts: Photocopy of typescripts of Eigner prose pieces (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "The Rest","A Turn", "Flue" - with some holographic notations.
  - Manuscript: Country/ Harbor/ Quiet/ Act /Around (Box 13, Folder 3)
    partial typescript w/ holographic notations carbon copy of typescript.
  - Manuscript: Photocopy of typescripts of Eigner prose pieces (Box 13, Folder 4)
    The Resort, "Even the Trees", "To the Plain" (re-titled "Through Plain") w/ revisions.
  - Manuscript: Photocopy of typescript w/ holographic notations in two binders. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Notebook:"C" holographic drafts of poetry (Dec 29, 1979 - Sept 9, 1986), Approx 60pp. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Notebook:"D" holographic drafts of poetry (1980-1983), 6pp. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Book: Country/ Harbor/ Quiet/ Act /Around (Kensington, CA: THIS, 1978). (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: Areas/ Lights/ Heights, Approx 200pp. (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    Typescript; proof pages of typescript; related correspondence (1965); photocopies of materials for manuscript.
- Prepatory Materials for Readings or Publications, Series 4
  Scope and Content of Series:
  Various materials of Eigner used in public readings of his work and preparing for publications.
  - #1: Booklet by Larry Eigner, There's a Season (tel-let, 1995). (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - #2: Photocopy of Object Permanence, #4 w/ Eigner poems. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - #3: Photocopies of five Eigner poems printed in magazines. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - #4: Photocopy of Introduction and Bio for Windows/ Walls/Yard/ Ways. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - #5: Rejected application for Guggenheim Grant, 1972. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - #6: Eigner printed poetry, (12 photocopies, 4 postcards, 1 pamphlet, 1 broadside). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - #7: Typed Eigner poems, 29pp (c1959). (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - #8: Photocopies of pages from Areas/Lights/Heights (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - #9: Photocopy of interview w/ Eigner in Kaleidoscope. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - #10: Photocopies of pages of critical writing by Eigner. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - #11: Photocopies of pages from St. Marks Poetry Project questionnaire w/ Eigner's responses. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - #12: Photocopies of material for Eigner tribute at UC Art Museum ( 7/ 25/ 93). (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - #13: Photocopies of notes for a tribute to Robert Duncan (4/ 4/ 58). (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - #14: Photocopies and carbons of Eigner Poems, 14pp. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - #15: Photocopies of pages from Lined up for Julk Senses. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - #16: Transcript of interview between Eigner and Ben Friedlander (1986). (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - #17: Photocopies of pages from Eigner books. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - #18: Photocopies of pages from Eigner books arranged for readings. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - #18: Photocopies of publication notes for Some Token or. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - #19: Photocopy of The-/Towards Autumn. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - #20: Photocopy of thmusic Variety. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - #21: 2 Photocopies of the poem My God The Proverbial. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - File #23: Photocopy of Flat and Round. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - #24: Partial photocopy of Anything on its Side w/ some holographic notations by Eigner. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - #25: Photocopy of Words Touching Ground Under. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - #26: Partial photocopy of Earth/ Birds. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Hemensley Manuscript. (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Material by Others, Series 5
  Material owned by Eigner, but not written by him. Contains correspondence from other writers, reviews of his work, work in progress for compilations, and copies of poetry by others writers.
  - #1: Photocopies of 2 poems by Peter Bates (1976) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #2: Photocopy of Jesse Beagle Poem, "Visit" w/ Larry Eigner, 6 pp. (6/ 12/ 1990). (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - #3: Photocopies of poetry and prose by Jack Foley, 20pp.(1986). (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - #4: Photocopies of poetry and prose by Jon Bernson, 1992, 20pp.(1986). (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - #5: Eigner review by Kit Robinson, 4pp. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - #6: Reviews of Eigner and his work, Approx 20pp. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - #7: Typed lists of Eigner poems and typescripts, Approx 50pp. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - #8: Photocopy of Robert Duncan interview, 40pp. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - #9: Unidentified Manuscripts (not Eigner), Approx 70pp. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - #10: Lists of Eigner work for Irving Leif Bibliography, Approx 25pp. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - #11: Publisher James Weil's page designs for Now There's a Morning Hunk of the Sky, 40pp. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - #12: Photocopies of draft letters for book of criticism (1965), Approx 40pp. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - #13: Photocopies of W. C. Williams poetry, 11 poems. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - #14: Typescript - "Four Poems for Larry Eigner" by Hunk Lazer (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - #15: Photocopies of various poetry, 15pp. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - #16: Transcripts and texts by Robert Grenier, Approx 30pp. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - #17: Various pamphlets, programs, bulletins - some w/holographic notations by Eigner. (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Definitive Versions of Eigner's Poetry, Series 6
  Definitive versions of Eigner works compiled by Robert Grenier under the direction of Larry Eigner. Most of this material is already at Kansas University Library.
  - List and descriptive history of Eigner/Grenier Collaboration. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: windows/ walls/ yard/ ways., Typescript, 175pp. (Box 17, Folder 2-6)
  - Manuscript: readiness/ enough/ depends/ on., Typescript, 128pp. (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
  - Untitled Manuscript: Typescript for as yet untitled collection of poems, Approx 200pp. (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
- Established Texts, Series 7
  Established texts of Larry Eigner's Poems (Approx 1700 pp)
  - Folder "D" (Feb 8, 1961 - June 6, 1965). (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Folder "E" (March 29, 1964 - Dec 31, 1965) (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
  - Folder "F" (Jan 1, 1966 - June 21, 1966). (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Poem #1 (June 29, 1966) - Poem #400 (June 18, 1970) (Box 18, Folder 6-9)
  - Poem #401 (June 19, 1970) - Poem #1124 (Feb 11, 1979). (Box 19)
  - Original Typescript of readiness/enough/depends/on; edited, typed, w/afterword by Robert Grenier (1995-6). (Othertype 20, Folder 1)
  - Original Typescript of waters/places/a time; edited, typed by Robert Grenier (1981) (Othertype 20, Folder 2)
- Additional Material: Preliminary Inventory, Series 8
  - Correspondence of Larry Eigner to his mother, Bessie Eigner and sister, Dot August 11, 1953 - October 29, 1989 - mostly from the early 80's, TLS, 55 letters (112p.), 56 postcards, three envelopes w/ holograph notations. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of Larry Eigner to Joe and Janet Eigner, November 1981 to December 1989, TLS, 20 letters (55p.) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Many include envelope w/ typed notations by Larry Eigner and reply from Joseph. Also includes 20 postcards from Larry Eigner to Joseph Eigner, sheets of typed poetry (photocopies), and newsclippings. 1. Object Permanence #4 (Photocopy) w/ letter to Joe and Janet Eigner (written by a third party) on reverse, July, 2 1995, signed "Larry" (Eigner); 2. ALS, 5 letters to Joe and Janet Eigner (written by a third party), July 1995 - December 1995, signed "Larry" (Eigner) w/ copies of Joseph's replies.
  - Joseph and Janet Eigner: Correspondence from Larry Eigner to Joseph and Janet Eigner, circa 1963 - 1976. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Many running to multiple pages and including copies of his poetry. Some of the letters are typed on paper scraps, backs of envelopes, and the reverse of letters sent to him. Also includes 6 postcards, 10 newsclippings, and copies of letters to Joe Eigner from other correspondents. 1. TLS, 52 letters, (122p.) to Joseph and Janet Eigner, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); 2. TLS(Carbon), 2 letters, (7p.) to Joseph and Janet Eigner, 1976, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); 3. TLS, 2p. to Richie (Eigner), May 15, 1976, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); 4. ALS, 1p. on reverse of birthday card. To "Joe" (Eigner), signed "Larry" (Eigner); 5. TLS, 5 letters. (9p.), 1971 - 1976, to "Children," signed "Mom" (Eigner); 6. TLS, 2p, signed "George Bowring"; 7. Typed (Poetry) Manuscript(Carbon), 7p., "A Miscellany for Vera Williams and Larry Eigner," signed in type "Jackson Mac Low"; 8. Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 17p.; 9. Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Photocopy), 4p.; 10. Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Carbon), 25p.